Guide to the Music, theatre, and spoken word sound recordings collection 1949-1986
George Mason University Special Collections & Archives
Music, theatre, and spoken word sound recordings collection
1949-1986
C0130
George Mason University Special Collections & Archives
1.25 linear feet (4 boxes)
This collection contains LP phonograph albums containing a variety of music, oral history, and musical scores. This box was found unlabeled and might be associated with another collection.
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Information
No information of donor or history is known.
Scope and Content
This collection contains 31 LP phonograph albums including music, musical scores, plays, literature recordings, and speech recordings. The albums span a roughly 40 year period being released between 1949 and the late 1980s. Musical albums include: A Tribute to Woodie Guthrie, Pete Seeger's Greatest Hits, Songs of the Depression, and I Will Win: Songs of the Wooblies. Albums of recorded plays feature playwrights such as William Shakespeare and Arthur Miller. The collection also features original cast recordings of musicals Winnie and Brigham!, a musical based on the life of Brigham Young and contains literary recordings of the works of T.S. Elliot, Frederick Douglass and Lorraine Hansberry.
Several of the albums focus on content related to the Great Depression, unions, American labor, and Folk Music.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donor unknown.
Related Archival Materials note
Special Collections and Archives also holds the Japanese Phonograph collection.
Arrangement note
The collection is not arranged in any specific order.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Acting.; Folk music--United States; Great Depression; Music--20th century.; Music.; Protest songs--United States
Document Types:
Live sound recordings.; Sound recordings.
- A Tribute to Woody Guthrie Part Two, 1972 (Box 1)
- Noel Coward's Bitter Sweet, 1961 (Box 1)
- George Gershwin's Song Book and Other Music for Piano Solo, 1986 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Preformed by Leonard Pennario.
- Song Recital (Vol. 1) Lotte Lehmann, Soprano with Eno Balogh at the Piano (Box 1)
- What if I am a Woman? Black Women's Speeches Narrated by Ruby Dee With an Introduction by Ossie Davis, 1977 (Box 1)
- Eubie Blake Song Hits, 1976 (Box 1)
- Speeches by Frederick Douglas read by Ossie Davis, 1977 (Box 1)
- Folk Music of the United States, 1952 (Box 1)
- William Shakespeare, The Taming of the Shrew, 1960 (Box 1)
- Songs of the FDR Years, 1979 (Box 1)
  Roy Berkeley and Tim Woodbridge
- Hard Times: The Story of the Depression in the Voices of those who Lived It., 1971 (Box 2)
- Strange, Unusual, Evening: A Santa Barbara Story, 1970 (Box 2)
- Brigham! Original Soundtrack, 1976 (Box 2)
- Arthur Miller's After the Fall, 1964 (Box 2)
  The Repertory Theater of Lincoln Center
- Promised Valley: Suit for Soloists, Chorus and Orchestra from the Musical Play, 1984 (Box 2)
- Winnie: Original Cast Recording, 1988 (Box 2)
- Judith Anderson in Medea, 1949 (Box 1)
- Sir John Gielgud and Miss Irene Worth in Men and Women of Shakespeare, 1967 (Box 2)
- Only the Music: Opera Without Words (Box 2)
- To be Young, Gifted and Black, 1970 (Box 3)
  Lorraine Hansberry
- Union Train, 1975 (Box 3)
  Joe Glazer
- I Will Win: Songs of the Wobblies, 1977 (Box 3)
- The Cradle Will Rock, 1964 (Box 3)
- The Labour Stage Production: Pins and Needles, 1962 (Box 3)
- Pete Seeger's Greatest Hits, 1967 (Box 3)
- Living Shakespeare: Hamlet, 1961 (Box 3)
- Songs of the Depression (Box 3)
- Negro Songs of Protest, 1973 (Box 3)
- Songs of Complaint and Protest, 1977 (Box 3)
- Twentieth Century Poetry in English: Contemporary Recordings of the Poets Reading Their Own Poems, 1949 (Box 4)
  T.S. Eliot
- The Smithsonian Collection of Classic Country Music, 1981 (Box 4)